<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Priuie Counsel. A commandement that no suiters come to the court for any priuate suite except their petitions be indorsed by the master of requests. 1594</title>
            <title>Proclamations. 1594</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Privy Council.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1595</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A21908</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 8239</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S115498</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99850717</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99850717</idno>
            <idno type="VID">15942</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A21908)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 15942)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 565:95)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Priuie Counsel. A commandement that no suiters come to the court for any priuate suite except their petitions be indorsed by the master of requests. 1594</title>
                  <title>Proclamations. 1594</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Privy Council.</author>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1558-1603 : Elizabeth I)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By the deputies of Christopher Barker, printer to the Queenes most excellent Maiestie,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1595.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England --  Court and courtiers --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Elizabeth, 1558-1603 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>England --  Proclamations --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:15942:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 14 -->
            <head>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> By the Priuie Counſel.</head>
            <head type="sub">A Commandement that no ſuiters come to the Court for any priuate ſuite except their petitions be indorſed by the Maſter of Requeſts. 1594.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas many and ſundry orders, haue bene formerly conceiued and publiſhed by Proclamtion, and other wiſe by her Maieſties expreſſe commandement, for the reſtraint of the vnordinate repayre of multitudes of Suitors to the Court, with Petitions and Complaints to her Maieſtie or her Priuie Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſell: wherof commonly the moſt part are for matters priuat, vnmeete to bee preferred to her, or for a Counſel of State to deale in: or be ſuch as are depen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding or decidable in ſome of her Maieſties Courtes of Iuſtice, or equitie at weſtminſter or other places in the Realme: which former orders are not ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerued, to the great diſtike of her Maieſtie, and the trouble and hinderance of her Counſell in the diſpatch of her Highneſſe important ſeruices: It is nowe therefore otrdered and inioyned that all Sutors, that from hencefoorth ſhall vpon coulour or cauſe of Suite, intend to exhibite complaint or petition to her Maieſtie or to her Counſell, ſhall firſt acquaint there with one of the Maſters of Requeſts, if any of them ſhalbe attendant in the Court, who with one of the Clerkes of the Counſell then attendant vpon hearing of the complaints, or vpon view and conſideration of their petitions, ſhall indorſe the ſubſtance of the matter, with their opinions ſubſcribed with their hands: But if the Maſter of Requeſts, ſhall bee out of the Court, ſo as the Clerke of the Counſell then attendant in the Court, cannot be preſent with the Maſter of the Requeſts at the hearing of the Complainant, then the Maſter of the Requeſts ſhall indorſe the Bill with his opinion, and ſhall ſend the ſame to the Clerke of the Counſell then attendant, who ſhall preſent the ſame to the Priuie Counſell at their next ſitting, to bee anſwered as ſhall bee found meete by the Counſell. And the Maſter of the Requeſts to referre the reſt of the Suitors, with their complaints to ordinarie Courtes of Iuſtice or equitie as the cauſe ſhall require: And to direct all other Suitors in cauſes, neither meete to be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferred to her Maieſtie, nor to be heard by the Priuie Counſell, nor yet meete for any other ordinarie Court of Iuſtice or equitie, to depart &amp; not to remaine as Suitors about the Court, vpon paine of impriſonment, and ſo to be committed by direction of the Maſters of Requeſts by warrant vnder his hand to the Knight Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhall or his Deputie.</p>
            <p>And the Maſter of the Requeſts ſhall alſo deliuer the names, of the parties that ſhall bee reiected, to the Queenes Maieſties Porter, to the intent he may know whom to exclude: and vpon the direction on the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaints ſo indorſed, the Suitors ſhall addreſſe themſelues to follow the ſaid direction, &amp; in no other ſort to folow their ſuites. And therefore it is ordred, that at ſuch time as any maner perſo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> (not being her Maieſties knowen ſeruant, or not of the degree &amp; condition of a known gentleman) ſhall offer to come in at the Court gates, as to be a Suitor, the Queens Maieſties Porters ſhall informe the partie of this order, and ſhall direct him or her to the Chamber of one of the Maſters of the Requeſts, if any of them ſhalbe in the Court: And if none of them ſhall be in the Court, then the Porters ſhall command the partie not to continue in the Court, but to repayre to the houſe of one of the Maſters of Requeſts, and afterwards as his petition ſhall be indorſed, he ſhall admit him to come into the Court, or reiect him: ſtraitly prohibiting all perſons not to preſſe in at the Court gate as Suitors, to exhibite any petition or complaint, without their Bill ſhall be firſt ſo endorſed by the ſayd Maſter of the Requeſts and Clerke of the Counſell as aboueſayd: or that the partie ſhall be licenſed by ſome of the pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uie Counſel, vpon ſpeciall cauſe knowen to repaire vnto the Court, to exhibite his complaint to the Queenes Maieſty, or to the Counſel, vpon paine of impriſonment in the Marſhalſeas, during their Lordſhips pleaſure.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>At the Court at Greenewich <date>the xx. of Auguſt. 1594.</date>
               </dateline>
               <lb/>
God ſaue the Queene</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> Imprinted at London by the Deputies of Chriſtopher Baker, Printer to the Queenes <hi>moſt excellent Maiestie.</hi> 1595.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
